Finding Aid for Arnold Weinstein papers, 1956-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Arnold Weinstein papers
1956-2013
Weinstein, Arnold.
2013066 Aa 2
Papers of Arnold Weinstein, American poet, playwright, librettist, and translator. Material in both paper and digital formats includes manuscript drafts and final versions of libretti, music scores with Weinstein's lyrics, manuscript and published literary works; research and background material related to individual works and projects, as well as programs, publicity material and reviews of shows. Also commercially produced and non-commercial audio and video recordings.
12.3 linear feet in 13 boxes including oversize
1 oversize volumes
956 MB online
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Collection was deposited by the Arnold Weinstein Intellectual Property Trust, Lisa Hamm and Stephen Hamm, Trustees (Donor no. 10951 ) in 2013. Additional material was donated by William Bolcom (Donor no. 8877 ) in 2013.
No further additions to the records are expected.
In making this deposit of Works to the Bentley, it is the intention of the Arnold Weinstein Intellectual Property Trust (AWIPT) that scholars, researchers and other third parties who meet the requirements of access set forth by the Bentley and other conditions in this Agreement shall have full access to the Works. However, the Bentley and/or users of the Works at the Bentley shall be subject to the following additional specific restrictions or other conditions:
The Works and underlying copyrights belong to the AWIPT and/or other third parties.
Uses of the deposited Works hereunder shall be for scholarship and research. The Bentley is not authorized to use or permit any commercial usage of the Works. All commercial usage of the Works shall be handled exclusively by the AWIPT. The Bentley will not use or authorize use of the Works for any commercial purposes, including but not limited to sale or license of Works, fee-for-service use of the Works, bulk reproduction or distribution of the Works or other services involving special charges to authorized users of the Works beyond reasonable administrative costs.
The Works are protected by copyright and permissions to use the Works must be obtained from the copyright owner for any uses of the Works other than for educational or research purposes. Users of the Works may not (i) remove, obscure or modify any copyright notices or other notices included in the Works, or (ii) use, or authorize the use of, Works in any manner that would infringe the copyright thereon.
All requests for permission to utilize the Works (utilize in any manner other than scholarship and/or research uses) shall be forwarded to and managed exclusively by the Trustees or the designers of the AWIPT or to any third party copyright holder of a Work(s). In the case of a request related to a Work with a copyright owned by a third, party, the Trustees will forward such request to the copyright owner of that Work.
Any use of Works for scholarship and/or research purposes must include standard academic attribution as follows: Arnold Weinstein Papers, Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan.
Born digital and digitized material stored on University of Michigan servers is accessible for use only in the Bentley Library reading room.
Arnold Weinstein was born in New York on June 10, 1927, to English-born parents Ada and Samuel Weinstein. During the World War II, at the age of 16, Weinstein enlisted in the U.S. Navy and served on a destroyer as a fireman. Instead of writing letters, he often wrote poems to his friends back at home.
After the War Weinstein studied Latin and Greek, and entered Hunter College (now Hunter College of the City University of New York) and graduated with a B.A. in 1951. As an undergraduate he also attended the University of London (1949-50). Weinstein then studied at Harvard University, earning a Rhodes scholarship and graduating with an M.A. in 1953. As a Fulbright fellow Weinstein continued his studies at University of Florence in 1958-1960. While in Florence, Weinstein met with William Bolcom, who was student of the French composer Darius Milhaud. Weinstein and Bolcom's decades-long friendship and artistic collaboration resulted in a great body of work.
In the 1950s-1960 Weinstein became affiliated with a group of poets, painters and musicians known as the New York School of Poets. Among his notable works of this period were The Red Eye of Love, a satire about an all-meat department store that had a long Off Broadway run in 1961, and an adaptation of Ovid's Metamorphoses (music by Tony Greco), which went to Broadway in 1971.
Weinstein started working on a play The Red Eye of Love before going to Florence in 1958. The play first saw the stage after Weinstein's return to the U.S. in 1960. In June 1961 The Red Eye of Love opened with music by William Bolcom and was well-received. The following year Weinstein's musical Fortuna, Francis Thorne composer, was opened. Weinstein returned to collaboration with Bolcom in 1963, creating Dynamite Tonite, which was produced by the Actor's Studio Theater, starring Barbara Harris and Alvin Epstein, Bolcom conducting. Dynamite Tonite was also produced by the Yale University School of Drama, and Weinstein was appointed Chair of the Yale Drama School Playwright Department in 1965-1969.
Weinstein's collaboration with Bolcom resulted in the operas McTeague (1991, premiered 1992); A View from the Bridge (with Arthur Miller, premiered 1999); A Wedding (with Robert Altman, premiered 2004). The operas have been commissioned by and premiered at the Chicago Lyric Opera. Their one-woman opera Medusa written for Catherine Malfitano was performed in 2003 at the Carnegie Hall. Weinstein and Bolcom also created four volumes of cabaret songs (Volumes I-II in 1978, and Volumes III-IV in 1997), musical theater works Greatshot (1968); Barnyard Boogaloo (1980); Casino Paradise (1986-1990); choral Maha Sonnet (1990); Miracle, madrigals for male chorus after Giovanni Pascoli (1999), The Wind in the Willows, with Paul Sills (1991-2001); Ancient Cabaret (2001); Idiot's Delight (2004); among other works.
Weinstein has worked with a number of important composers throughout his career, notably with composer Philip Glass; contemporary classical composer Francis Thorne; composer, arranger, and conductor for theater, television and film Laurence Rosenthal; the University of Michigan faculty member, composer, conductor, and pianist Bright Sheng; composer, conductor, performer and author David Amram; director and composer Tony Greco; the founder of Chicago's Second City Theater Paul Sills; painters Andy Warhol, Marisol, Larry Rivers, Howard Kanovitz; scenic designer Robin Wagner; among other performing and visual artists.
Translation was important area of Weinstein's theater work. Weinstein created a new translation of Berthold Brecht-Kurt Weill's 1931 Mahagonny for the United States premiere in 1970. He also translated works of classical poets for Ancient Cabaret and Metamorphoses; from Federico Garcia Lorca for Gypsy New York (music by Tony Greco, 1974); and others.
Weinstein taught English, creative writing, and playwriting at New York University, the University of Southern California, Los Angeles, Rutgers University, Yale University and Columbia University. He also served as Director of the drama workshop at Wagner College, summer writers conference, beginning in 1963.
Arnold Weinstein died in New York on September 4, 2005.
The collection contains paper, analog, and digital materials and is organized into four series: Personal/Biographical, Theater, Writing, and Audio-Visual Materials.
The Papers of Arnold Weinstein collection documents the work of the American librettist, playwright and poet between the late 1950s through the 2000s.
Subjects:
Weinstein, Arnold.; Dramatists--United States.; Librettists--United States.; Music theater--Scores.; Music theater--United States.; Musicals--Librettos.; Opera--United States.; Operas--Librettos.; Operas--Scores and parts.; Poets--United States.; Songs--Texts.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bolcom, William.; Morris, Joan, 1943-; Weinstein, Arnold.; Music theater.; Opera.; Operas and librettos.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Weinstein, Arnold.; Live sound recordings.; Music theater.; Opera.
Contributors:
Bolcom, William.; Greco, Tony.; Rivers, Larry, 1925-2002.; Sheng, Bright, 1955-
Genre Terms:
Audiocassettes.; CD-ROMs.; Interview.; Musical.; Opera.; Photographs.; Video recordings.; Videotapes.; Sound recordings.
- Personal/Biographical
  - Awards, 1971; 2002; .ZIP file
    [Download Access Restricted to BHL Reading Room]
  - Biographies and obituaries, .ZIP file (Box 1)
  - Clippings, circa 1961-1990; .ZIP file
  - Correspondence, .ZIP file
    - By Weinstein 1944-1988 scattered years and undated (Box 1)
    - To Weinstein, 1982-2005; undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Various, undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Family, Friends, and Performances, circa 1960-2000; .ZIP file
  - Resume (update), circa 1988; .ZIP file
  - Miscellaneous personal items, undated (Box 1)
- Theater
  - Index of Theatrical Works and Songs Transferred by the Weinstein Intellectual Trust, 2013; .XLSX and .TXT files (Box 1)
  - American Revolution
    (music by Tony Greco)
    - Libretti, 2002; undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Music score, 1976; undated (Box 1)
    - Project file, 1973; undated (Box 1)
  - Ancient Cabaret, 2001; 2005; undated (Box 1)
    (music by William Bolcom)
  - Artists in Residence (Box 1)
    (concept)
  - Barnyard Boogaloo, circa 1980; .ZIP file (Box 1)
    in manuscript and digital formats; music by William Bolcom
  - Blue Light, undated; .ZIP file (Box 1)
    (in manuscript and digital formats; dramatic piece)
  - Cabaret Songs
    - Analysis: The "Cabaret Songs," Volume One of William Bolcom and Arnold Weinstein: an Exploration and Analysis (Master's thesis by Marlene Titus Bateman), 2001 (Box 1)
    - "Black Max"
      - Project file, 1979; 1985 (Box 1)
      - Music score, outsize, 1978-1985 (Box 9)
      - Review: "De Kooning's Rotterdam Days,", 1986; .ZIP file
    - Cabaret Songs Volumes 1-4, 1985; 1997; 2 volumes (Box 1)
    - Last Lousy Moments, 1970s; 2000 (Box 1)
    - Music score and publicity material (Box 1)
    - Programs, 1986-2004; undated (Box 1)
    - Reviews, 1986-2004; undated (Box 1)
    - Song lyrics, undated; .ZIP file (Box 1)
      (in manuscript and digital formats)
  - Café Classico (Box 1)
  - Casino Paradise: a Cabaret Opera
    - Music Score
      - Outsize, 1987-1988; 2005 (Box 9)
      - 1991, 1995; undated; 5 folders (Box 1)
      - 1991, 1995; undated (Box 2)
    - Libretti
      - 1989-1990, 2004; undated; 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Drafts and various scenes and songs, circa 1990; .ZIP file
    - Programs and publicity material, 1990-2005 (Box 2)
    - Reviews, 1986; 1990-1992; 2004 (Box 2)
    - Vocal score (Box 2)
  - Cleopatra: Three Songs (Box 2)
    (music by Laurence Rosenthal)
  - The Dreamer: An Opera in Two Acts
    (music by Charles Schwarz)
    - Libretto and Review, undated (Box 2)
    - Libretto Drafts and Plot Outline, undated; .PDF
  - Dynamite Tonite
    - "Gosh, I Can't Believe It's True Blues,", undated (Box 2)
    - Libretti
      - 1964, undated (Box 2)
      - Drafts (with possible revisions), 2001; .ZIP file
    - Music score, outsize, undated (Box 9)
    - Piano/vocal score, 1967 (Volume 1)
    - Reviews, programs and publicity material, 1966-1987; undated (Box 2)
  - Dynamo, 2004-2005 and undated (Box 2)
  - Final Ingredient: a Passover Opera, 1965 (Box 2)
    (music by David Amram)
  - Food for Thought, undated (Box 2)
    (with Fran Landesman, music by Lawrence Rosenthal and Jimmy Williams)
  - Fortuna, 1960s; 2001 (Box 2)
    (music by Frances Thorne)
  - Galileo Galilei, 2002 and undated; .ZIP file (Box 2)
    (in manuscript and digital formats; music by Philip Glass; digital version includes multiple drafts and notes addressed to Glass)
  - General Opera
    (music by William Russo)
    - Libretti, 1977; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Music score, 1977; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Greatshot: an Opera for Actors; a Play without Words
    - Libretto (Box 2)
    - Music score, outsize, 1969; undated (Box 10)
    - Drafts of Lyrics and Libretti, undated; .ZIP file
  - Gypsy New York, undated (Box 2)
    (see Lorca, NY)
  - Half Meeting: a Burlesque, undated (Box 2)
  - Hamlet: the Musical, undated (Box 2)
    (by Shel Silverstein)
  - Hansel and Gretel, 1964; undated (Box 2)
  - Hermits, undated (Box 2)
  - Idiot's Delight, undated; .ZIP file (Box 2)
    (in manuscript and digital formats; music by William Bolcom)
  - Lady Liberty (Living Theatre), undated; .ZIP file 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Lorca, NY
    - Libretto (Box 3)
    - Music score (Box 3)
    - Project file, 1985; undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Lyrics, Translated Poetry, and Biographical Sketch of Frederico Garcia Lorca, undated; .ZIP file
  - Lysistrata (working title: Liz Estrada), undated; .ZIP file
    (Proposal, lyrics, and related materials)
  - Maha Sonnet, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Mahagonny
    (adapted from Bertolt Brecht, music by Kurt Weill)
    - Libretti, undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Music score, 1956; 1969; 3 volumes (Box 3)
    - Project file (Box 3)
    - Reviews, 1970s-2000 (Box 3)
    - Drafts of Libretti, undated; .ZIP file
  - McTeague
    - Reviews and miscellaneous, 1992; 2004-2005 (Box 3)
    - Vocal Score, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Outline, Notes, and Lyrics, circa 2005; .ZIP file
      (Notes and lyrics appear to be from a proposed revision of McTeague for the 2006-2007 season of the Lyric Opera of Chicago)
  - Medusa
    - Music score, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Project file, 2003; undated (Box 3)
    - Vocal/Piano score, outsize, 2002 (Box 10)
    - Notes and Lyrics (multiple drafts), circa 2002; .ZIP file
  - Metamorphoses
    - Libretti, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Music score, outsize (Box 10)
    - Project file (Box 3)
    - Publicity, reviews, 1970s-1990s (Box 3)
    - Drafts of Libretti, undated; .ZIP file
  - Miracle: Nine Madrigals after Giovanni Pascoli, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Monkey
    (see also Story Theatre)
    - Book and lyrics by Arnold Weinstein from the Paul Sills "Story Theatre,", 1994 (Box 4)
    - Book by Arnold Weinstein and Paul Sills, undated; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Milwaukee production, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Project file, 1978; 2002; undated (Box 4)
    - Additional work files, circa 1994; .ZIP file
  - Monkey King: A Martial Arts Musical
    (music by Bright Sheng)
    - King of the Mountain, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Project file, 2004-2005; 2007; undated; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Notes, Plot Descriptions, and Drafts of Lyrics, circa 2004; .ZIP file
  - Mr. & Mrs. & Mr. (Box 4)
    (with Rhoda Roberts and Kenneth Jacobson, music by Kenneth Jacobson)
  - Nervous Set (Box 4)
    (by Fran Landesmann, music by Tommy Wolf)
  - Old Addresses
    - Drafts, 2001 (Box 4)
      (music by William Bolcom; includes versions of "Africa: Adapted from a Prison Letter by George Jackson")
    - Lyrics related to George Jackson, circa 2001 (Box 4)
  - Pal Joey, 2003; .ZIP file
    (Notes and drafts of lyrics and dialogue)
  - Parables of Chuang Chu, undated; .ZIP file
  - The Party
    - Early version, undated; .ZIP file
    - Fifty, 1983; .ZIP file (Box 4)
      (Revised version; in manuscript and digital formats)
    - Libretto (Box 4)
    - Music sheets (Box 4)
    - Programs and reviews, 1977; 1982; circa 1985 (Box 4)
    - Project file (Box 4)
    - Music score, outsize (Box 10)
  - Play of Consciousness
    (music by William Bolcom, William Russo, Laurence Rosenthal, Daniel Schreier, and others)
    - Baba (earlier version), circa 1978; undated (Box 4)
    - Libretto (Box 4)
    - Drafts of Lyrics and Libretti, undated; .ZIP file
    - Project file, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Punch & Judy Get Divorced, 1996; .ZIP file (Box 5)
    (in manuscript and digital formats; with David and Ain Gordon, music by Edward Barnes)
  - Red Eye of Love
    - Music by William Bolcom, 1961-1963; 1978; 1992; undated (Box 5)
      (dramatic work)
    - Music by Jan Warner, 1984-2008 (Box 5)
    - Music by Sam Davis, 2013 (Box 5)
    - Programs, Lyrics, Song Sheets and Scripts, 1961-2013; .ZIP file
      (Includes multiple productions)
  - Reg. US Pat. Off. (Box 5)
  - Rigoletto, circa 1997; .ZIP file (Box 5)
    (in manuscript and digital formats; proposal, lyrics, and libretto)
  - Riot: An Hysterical Drawing Room Comedy
    - Baldwin, 1978; undated (Box 5)
      (Alternate version)
    - Music sheets (Box 5)
    - Now Nasrudine (Box 5)
    - Project file, 1968-2004; undated (Box 5)
    - Various Notes and Drafts for Baldwin and Riot, undated; .ZIP file
      (May also contain material related to Rigoletto, Tupelo, and other works.)
  - Round the Christmas Table, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Shlemiel the First
    (music by Hankus Netsky and Zalman Mlatek)
    - Libretti, 1994-2009; 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Music score (Box 5)
    - Programs, publicity, reviews (Box 5)
    - Notes and Drafts of Lyrics and Libretti, undated; .ZIP file
  - Starving (Box 5)
  - Story Theatre
    (see also Monkey)
    - Ovid music sheets, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Paul Sills' Story Theater Four Shows (Box 5)
      (New York, London: 2000)
    - Project file, 1970s-2004; undated (Box 5)
    - Scripts (Box 5)
  - Taco Dilemma (Box 5)
  - They (A Mystical Farce)
    - Old versions, 1994; undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Script (Box 6)
    - Drafts of Libretti, undated; .ZIP file
  - To Find another Island (Box 6)
  - Tupelo
    (with Kevin Eggers; music by Anthony Davis)
    - Elvis'56: In the Beginning by Alfred Wertheimer (Box 6)
      (New York: 1979)
    - Libretti, 2002; undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Music score, 1999-2000 (Box 6)
    - Drafts of Lyrics and Libretti (with 'master' version), circa 2002; .ZIP file
  - Twenty Five Cent White Summer Cap (Box 6)
  - Undercover Lover: a Musical Comedy, undated; .ZIP file (Box 6)
    (in manuscript and digital formats; with Frank O'Hara, music by John Gruen)
  - Vain and the Venal (Box 6)
  - A View from the Bridge
    (with Arthur Miller; music by William Bolcom)
    - Libretti
      - English, 1999 (Box 6)
      - German, 2002 (Box 6)
      - Italian and English, 2011 (Box 6)
    - Photographs (Box 6)
    - Programs, 1999-2005 (Box 6)
    - Reviews, publicity, 1999-2005 (Box 6)
    - Vocal score, 2001-2002; 3 volumes (Box 6)
    - Drafts of Lyrics and Libretti, circa 1999; .ZIP file
  - W. C., undated; .ZIP file (Box 6)
    (in manuscript and digital formats; with Fran Landesman, music by Laurence Rosenthal)
  - Ward Six, undated; .ZIP file 2 folders (Box 6)
    (in manuscript and digital formats; music by Lukas Foss)
  - A Wedding
    (based on the film by Robert Altman; music by William Bolcom)
    - Libretti, 2004; undated (Box 7)
    - Music score, 2003/2003-2004, 4 volumes (Box 7)
    - Reviews, programs, publicity, 2004-2005 (Box 7)
    - Drafts of Lyrics and Libretti, circa 2003-2004; .ZIP file
      (Also contains poems, presumably by Weinstein)
  - Wind in the Willows
    (with Paul Sills, music by William Bolcom)
    - Libretti (Box 7)
      - 1996-1997, 2001; 4 folders (Box 7)
      - 1983-2001, .ZIP file
    - Music score, outsize (Box 10)
    - Production materials (North Haven, Conn.), 1997 (Box 7)
    - Programs, publicity, reviews, 1998-2004 (Box 7)
  - Posters, Playbills, and Promotional Stills (various), circa 1961-2000; .ZIP file
  - Idea Files, circa 1980s-2000s; .ZIP file
    (Includes notes, outlines, and drafts for essays, theater pieces, and Larry Rivers autobiography)
  - Various Solos, Songs, and Stories, undated; .ZIP file
    (Collected poems, lyrics, and scripts by Weinstein, including)
- Writing
  - Arianna a Naxos (Box 7)
    (translation from Latin)
  - Articles and Essays
    - Various, 1967-2002 (Box 7)
    - "A Romance with the Classics", 2001; .ZIP file
      (Drafts and research materials for an article about A. E. Housman written for the Lincoln Center Theater Review's Spring 2001 issue on Tom Stoppard's The Invention of Love)
    - Essays on Poetry, Artists, and Critics, 1987-1988; undated; .ZIP file
  - Poems
    - Manuscript
      - 1956, undated; 3 folders (Box 7)
      - "Life Isn't Everything: The Theater Poetry of Arnold Weinstein,", circa 1999; .DOCX files
        (Selected works, with afterword by John Guare)
      - Various Lyrics and Poems, circa 1951-2000; .ZIP file
        - Acting
        - After Garcia Lorca
        - Airs Academica
        - The Argument
        - Heavenly Storm: A Drama
        - Ballad #1
        - The Big Flood
        - The Birth
        - Blame, Blame, Blame
        - Bout the War
        - The Boy Proust
        - Breakfast Ballad
        - Candy Store
        - Central Park March 21
        - Chrysler Building: A Song
        - Circe
        - Cliché
        - Combat
        - Dead Man's Tale
        - The Limited Privilege of Distraction!
        - "Epithalamion"
        - Evangelist on Times Square
        - For the Marriage of Violet Lang and Bradley Phillips
        - From an Undiscovered Latin Poem
        - From an Undiscovered Latin Poem
        - Pigeons
        - Garcia Lorca Slept Here
        - Dead Man's Tale
        - Heidi
        - Hello
        - His Last Memo
        - History Suite
        - Husband
        - In the Garden
        - From the Jersey Side
        - Juno's Song
        - Lady Dancing in the Street
        - Lady Dancing in the Street
        - Lecture (Draft)
        - Exhibition (!)
        - Night Had a Crack In It
        - So Should I become?
        - Mantra
        - The Marriage: an Historical Play in 16 acts for Helen and Robert Motherwell
        - Microscopy
        - Millie
        - Monsters
        - Moon in the Morning
        - Night Letter
        - N.Y., New York
        - Of Love and You
        - Phaethon
        - Paolo Uccello and St. Francis. after Giovanni Pascoli, "Poet Signature
        - Paradise Lost
        - Pickles
        - Please: A Life
        - Please: Another Life
        - Africa
        - Ballad of the Outskirts
        - Chicago
        - Creation Blues
        - Eyes of, 1910
        - The Forge; The Forge of Ambiguity
        - Garden of, 1956
        - George Grosz
        - The Little Knife
        - Lorca Harlem
        - Love in the Thirties
        - Madonna
        - Mike
        - No More Umbrella Fella
        - Preparing for Winter, or Summer
        - Pygmalion
        - Shakti's Song
        - Soutine
        - The Ball Player
        - The Body
        - Eat
        - Greetings
        - My Husbands Don't Understand Me
        - Packed with Action: An Action Packed Play Without Words [An Action Packed Drama]
        - Paradise in the form of a mall
        - Poor Money
        - Screambags
        - Thinking of You
        - Goodbye Note
        - Cell Phone
        - The Coo and the Mannie (From a Highlands song)
        - Da Ponte on Broadway
        - I Hate Vegetables/That's How Meat Began
        - Irving
        - The Market Lady
        - The Red and the Black
        - ""Teach Him"
        - Teach Mama"
        - Waiting for the Next Millennium
        - Poetry
        - Poetry a digital and paper folder
        - Poetry (a poem)
        - Portraits of Painters, 1956
        - Real Household
        - Satisfactions
        - Poem: He Tipped the Waiter (Serenata)
        - Surprise
        - [Sickel] Seems to me
        - Situations: Learning
        - As You Come From the Holy Land
        - Art Songs, That Is, Songs About Art
        - Something to be Said
        - Redcoats and Redskins (a chiefs tepee)
        - Nobody Else But Me
        - Cock Robin (adapted from some old thing)
        - Spin Around the Moon
        - St. Germain Des Pres
        - Thanks
        - The TV Play Within the TV Play
        - The Ugly Bar, Sc. 4 Song No. 8